100 years later, lightning strikes twice.
Titanic II is a action, thriller, romance film directed by Shane van Dyke.
On the 100th anniversary of the original voyage, a modern luxury liner
christened "Titanic 2," follows the path of its namesake.
But when a tsunami hurls an ice berg into the new ship's path, the
passengers and crew must fight to avoid a similar fate.
Hayden Walsh, played by Shane van Dyke.
Amy Maine, played by Marie Westbrook.
James Maine, played by Bruce Davison.
Dr. Kim Patterson, played by Brooke Burns.
Kelly Wade, played by Michelle Glavan.
Elmer Coolidge, played by Carey van Dyke.
Titanic II is a 2010 American drama disaster film written, directed by
and starring Shane Van Dyke and distributed by the Asylum.
It is not a sequel to the 1997 film.
The film is set on a fictional replica Titanic that sets off exactly 100 years after the original ship's maiden voyage to perform the reverse route, but
global warming and the forces of nature cause history to repeat itself on the same night, only on a more disastrous and deadly scale.
Titanic II was released direct-to-TV in Australia on August 7, 2010.
It was released on August 25 in the United States to critically negative response, though the
film's ensemble cast performances, particularly that of Bruce Davison, received praise.
A supernatural horror-themed sequel, Titanic 666, was
released twelve years later, in 2022.
The film explores themes of iceberg, titanic, bad
weather, cruise liner, commemoration.
The tone is emotional and intense.